(Only For Love)
(사랑만을 위해서)
(Episode 11)
(제11화)
Hi, may I know who ordered this?
안녕하세요, 누가 주문했는지 알 수 있을까요?
Here.
여기.
Well, someone here wants cake.
음, 여기 케이크를 원하는 사람이 있어요.
(Shi Yan, I can't believe you're subtly mocking me here.)
(시얀, 당신이 여기서 나를 교묘하게 조롱하고 있다는 게 믿기지 않네요.)
Hurry up and eat.
서둘러서 먹어라.
Wait for me. I'm going to say hi to Uncle Cheng.
날 기다려. 청삼촌께 인사드리러 가겠습니다.
Okay.
좋아요.
Looks like Shi Yan finally found a new girlfriend.
Shi Yan이 마침내 새로운 여자친구를 찾은 것 같습니다.
I heard that he was devastated after Bei Lin dumped him.
Bei Lin이 그를 차버린 후 그는 충격을 받았다고 들었습니다.
That's why he left Mingyu.
그래서 민규를 떠났다.
That's how the nickname "Mingyu Runaway Prince" came about.
그래서 '민규 가출왕자'라는 별명도 생겼다.
That's not right.
그건 맞지 않습니다.
Shi Yan left Mingyu at the most critical time.
Shi Yan은 가장 중요한 순간에 Mingyu를 떠났습니다.
Bei Lin dumped him because she thought he wasn't responsible.
Bei Lin은 그에게 책임이 없다고 생각하여 그를 차버렸습니다.
Do you think that girl
그 여자 생각하니?
knows all the things that happened to Shi Yan?
Shi Yan에게 일어난 모든 일을 알고 있나요?
Why does it matter?
그것이 왜 중요합니까?
Everyone takes what they need.
모두가 필요한 것을 가져갑니다.
Do you think the girl fell for Shi Yan solely because of his handsome looks
그 소녀가 오로지 그의 잘생긴 외모 때문에 Shi Yan에게 반했다고 생각하시나요?
and not his background or wealth?
그의 배경이나 재산도 아니고?
Makes sense.
말이된다.
When did you come back?
언제 돌아 왔어?
Just now.
방금.
Really? Just now?
정말? 방금?
What's up? Do you want to eat or drink something?
무슨 일이야? 뭔가 먹고 싶거나 마시고 싶나요?
I'm tired. Let's go back.
피곤해요. 돌아가자.
Let's go.
갑시다.
Let's send Miss Zheng home first.
먼저 정 씨를 집으로 보내자.
Okay, Mr. Shi.
알았어, 시 씨.
Looks like Shi Yan finally found a new girlfriend.
Shi Yan이 마침내 새로운 여자친구를 찾은 것 같습니다.
What does it have to do with you if he finds a girlfriend?
그가 여자친구를 찾으면 당신과 무슨 상관이 있나요?
I heard that he was devastated after Bei Lin dumped him.
Bei Lin이 그를 차버린 후 그는 충격을 받았다고 들었습니다.
That's why he left Mingyu.
그래서 민규를 떠났다.
What kind of nonsense are you talking?
무슨 말도 안되는 소리를하고 있습니까?
He was full of ambition and left to start his own business.
그는 야망으로 가득 차 있었고 자신의 사업을 시작하기 위해 떠났습니다.
That's how the nickname "Mingyu Runaway Prince" came about.
그래서 '민규 가출왕자'라는 별명도 생겼다.
Did you see him run away with your own eyes?
그 사람이 도망가는 걸 직접 눈으로 봤나요?
Can't you see him?
그 사람이 보이지 않나요?
That's not right. The version I heard was Shi Yan left Mingyu
그건 맞지 않습니다. 내가 들었던 버전은 Shi Yan이 민규를 떠났다는 것이었습니다.
at the most critical time.
가장 중요한 순간에.
Bei Lin dumped him because she thought he wasn't responsible.
Bei Lin은 그에게 책임이 없다고 생각하여 그를 차버렸습니다.
Did you hide under his bed?
그의 침대 밑에 숨었나요?
How did you know who was being dumped?
누가 버림받았는지 어떻게 알았나요?
What do you mean by not responsible? He was obviously shouldering
책임이 없다니 무슨 뜻인가요? 그 사람은 분명히 어깨를 으쓱하고 있었어
the responsibility of the whole Mingyu Yunchuang.
Mingyu Yunchuang 전체의 책임입니다.
Do you think that girl
그 여자 생각하니?
knows all the things that happened to Shi Yan?
Shi Yan에게 일어난 모든 일을 알고 있나요?
That's none of your business.
그거 너랑 상관 없어.
What does it matter?
그것은 무슨 상관이야?
Everyone takes what they need.
모두가 필요한 것을 가져갑니다.
Do you think that girl fell for Shi Yan solely
그 여자가 오로지 Shi Yan에게 반했다고 생각하시나요?
because of his handsome looks
잘생긴 외모 때문에
and not his background or wealth?
그의 배경이나 재산도 아니고?
I don't believe it.
나는 그것을 믿지 않는다.
Why can't I fall for Shi Yan's handsome looks?
왜 시옌의 잘생긴 외모에 반할 수 없는 걸까요?
Even if I'm after his money, what does it have to do with you?
내가 그 사람 돈을 쫓는다고 해도 그게 너랑 무슨 상관이야?
Thanks for treating me to dinner today, Mr. Shi.
오늘 저에게 저녁을 대접해 주셔서 감사합니다, Mr. Shi.
I'm going home first.
나 먼저 집에 갈 거야.
Zheng Shu Yi.
정슈이.
I'm calling you. Didn't you hear me?
나는 당신에게 전화하고 있습니다. 내 말 못 들었어?
I heard you.
들었어.
Are you in such a hurry to go home?
집에 가려고 그렇게 서두르나요?
No, not really.
아니 정말.
Are you in a hurry to go home to bake small cakes?
작은 케이크를 굽기 위해 서둘러 집에 가시나요?
Shi Yan.
시얀.
You're so annoying.
너 진짜 짜증 난다.
You stopped me just to say that?
그런 말을 하려고 날 막았나요?
What else do you want to hear?
또 무엇을 듣고 싶나요?
Why aren't you happy?
왜 행복하지 않나요?
Nothing.
아무것도 아님.
So, what did you gain from tonight's dinner?
그럼 오늘 저녁 식사에서 무엇을 얻었나요?
I did hear some things about you, Mr. Shi.
당신에 대해 몇 가지 이야기를 들었습니다, 시 씨.
So, do you believe it?
그래서, 당신은 그것을 믿습니까?
Of course, I don't.
물론 그렇지 않습니다.
I only believe what you tell me.
나는 당신이 나에게 말하는 것만 믿습니다.
So, do you want to know more about me?
그럼 나에 대해 더 알고 싶나요?
Can't I?
나는 할 수 없습니까?
So, you're not in a hurry to go home.
그러니 집에 가기 위해 서두르지 마세요.
I'm not in a hurry.
나는별로 급하지 않아.
What do you want me to say?
당신은 내가하고 싶은 말이?
Isn't what they said quite complete?
그들이 말한 것이 아주 완전하지 않습니까?
My past experiences,
나의 과거 경험,
from life to work,
생활부터 일까지,
they talked about everything.
그들은 모든 것에 대해 이야기했습니다.
(So, he heard it all.)
(그래서 그는 그것을 모두 들었습니다.)
Did they hide under your table or under your bed?
테이블 밑이나 침대 밑에 숨어 있었나요?
How could they know everything about you?
그들이 어떻게 당신에 관한 모든 것을 알 수 있습니까?
If we can judge a person just by hearsay and a few meetings,
소문과 몇 번의 만남만으로 사람을 판단할 수 있다면,
then I can also say, in my eyes,
그러면 나도 내 눈에는 이렇게 말할 수 있다.
you are a wise and far-sighted,
당신은 현명하고 통찰력이 있는 사람입니다.
excellent and handsome young entrepreneur.
훌륭하고 잘생긴 젊은 기업가.
I wouldn't know that if you didn't say it.
당신이 말하지 않았다면 나는 그것을 몰랐을 것입니다.
So, I'm so excellent in your eyes?
그럼 니 눈엔 내가 그렇게 훌륭해?
I'm just giving an example.
나는 단지 예를 제시하고 있습니다.
It's not clear to me who you really are.
당신이 실제로 누구인지는 확실하지 않습니다.
Is it clearer now?
이제 좀 더 명확해졌나요?
You can't park here.
여기에는 주차할 수 없습니다.
Miss Zheng, are you okay?
정 씨, 괜찮으세요?
I'm fine.
잘 지내요.
(Please enter the password.)
(비밀번호를 입력해주세요.)
(Door is opened.)
(문이 열려있습니다.)
Seven.
일곱.
Don't stand there. Hurry up and go.
거기 서 있지 마세요. 서둘러서 가세요.
Mr. Shi, do I need to send the clothes in the trunk to Miss Zheng?
Shi 선생님, 트렁크에 있는 옷을 Miss Zheng에게 보내야 하나요?
No need. Let's go.
필요 없음. 갑시다.
(Shu Yi, what are you talking about?)
(슈이, 무슨 소리 하는 거야?)
(Have you been drinking too much?)
(너무 많이 마셨나?)
(Shu Yi, are you okay?)
(슈이 씨, 괜찮아요?)
(What's wrong with you?)
(왜 그래?)
(Don't you know that lightning could strike you)
(번개가 당신을 칠 수 있다는 것을 모르십니까?)
(for disturbing people so late?)
(너무 늦게 사람들을 방해해서?)
You did well.
잘했어요.
You must let him know that there are other guys who are after you.
당신을 쫓는 다른 남자들이 있다는 것을 그에게 알려주어야 합니다.
Don't you see that he's falling for it?
그 사람이 그것에 빠지고 있는 게 보이지 않나요?
Otherwise, why would he be implying things to you, all right?
그렇지 않다면 왜 그 사람이 당신에게 그런 암시를 하겠나요?
I guess he will dream of you tonight.
오늘 밤 그 사람이 당신 꿈을 꿀 것 같아요.
(But you must not give him any response.)
(단, 그 사람에게 어떤 대답도 해서는 안 됩니다.)
We should keep him guessing.
우리는 그가 계속 추측하도록 해야 합니다.
Let him take the initiative to find and chase you.
그가 주도적으로 당신을 찾고 쫓도록 하세요.
Listen to me.
내 말을 들어보세요.
Don't worry about what he thinks of you.
그가 당신을 어떻게 생각하는지 걱정하지 마세요.
What is the nature of men?
남자의 본성은 무엇입니까?
It's conquering.
정복하고 있습니다.
If you don't have someone chasing you, or if you're too easy to get,
쫓아오는 사람이 없거나 너무 잡기 쉽다면
(he won't treasure you.)
(그는 당신을 소중히 여기지 않을 것이다.)
You have to find a way to make him take the initiative.
그가 주도권을 갖도록 하는 방법을 찾아야 합니다.
What for you pursue him unilaterally?
일방적으로 그를 쫓아다니는 게 어때서?
(Then, what?)
(그리고 뭐?)
Then...
그 다음에...
Then, I called you.
그러다가 당신에게 전화했어요.
Nothing happened after that?
그 이후에는 아무 일도 일어나지 않았나요?
So, he sent you home.
그래서 그는 당신을 집으로 보냈습니다.
(But nothing happened between you two.)
(그러나 두 사람 사이에는 아무 일도 일어나지 않았습니다.)
Then, I went home.
그리고 나는 집에 갔다.
All right then. I won't chat with you now.
그럼요. 이제 당신과 채팅하지 않겠습니다.
I still have something to do here.
아직 여기서 할 일이 있어요.
(Wait and see.)
(기다려보세요.)
(Keep a distance.)
(거리를 유지하세요.)
Wine is not bad.
와인은 나쁘지 않습니다.
The wine glass is too cold.
와인잔이 너무 차갑습니다.
You have so many tricks.
당신은 많은 트릭을 가지고 있습니다.
Aren't you afraid someone will be sincere to you?
누군가가 당신에게 진심이 될까봐 두렵지 않나요?
It's best not to.
그러지 않는 것이 가장 좋습니다.
He can't get out of it.
그는 그것에서 벗어날 수 없습니다.
You...
너...
What's wrong?
뭐가 문제 야?
Nothing.
아무것도 아님.
I'm fine.
잘 지내요.
What are you doing?
뭐하세요?
Let me get changed. I'll take you to the hospital.
옷을 갈아입게 해주세요. 병원에 데려다 줄게.
I'm not going.
나는 가지 않을 것이다.
It's swollen.
부어 있어요.
I have an appointment tomorrow.
내일 약속이 있어요.
Hello?
안녕하세요?
Send me some band-aids. I...
반창고 좀 보내주세요. 나...
Unilateral efforts are indeed meaningless.
일방적인 노력은 정말 의미가 없습니다.
With what happened today,
오늘 있었던 일로,
I don't even know what he wants.
나는 그가 무엇을 원하는지조차 모릅니다.
Actually, everyone knows that
사실 다들 아는 사실인데
more efficient and safer batteries are always
더 효율적이고 안전한 배터리는 항상
the pain points for the development of the new energy vehicle industry.
신에너지 자동차 산업 발전의 페인포인트.
So, finding a battery enterprise with potential for long-term development
그래서 장기적으로 발전 가능성이 있는 배터리 기업을 찾는다.
is the most important key for us to enter this line of business.
우리가 이 사업 분야에 진입하는 데 가장 중요한 열쇠입니다.
Zhanlan's market share is high now.
현재 Zhanlan의 시장 점유율은 높습니다.
After this round of financing,
이번 펀딩 라운드 이후,
it will definitely go up another level.
확실히 다른 수준으로 올라갈 것입니다.
Zhanlan is indeed a good choice,
Zhanlan은 정말 좋은 선택입니다.
but the competition is fierce.
하지만 경쟁이 치열해요.
Many companies are now confident of their success.
이제 많은 기업들이 성공을 확신하고 있습니다.
Zhanlan is in a leading position in the industry,
Zhanlan은 업계 최고의 위치에 있으며,
but can they break through
하지만 돌파할 수 있을까
the technical difficulty of all-solid-state batteries
전고체전지의 기술적 어려움
and continue to lead the industry?
계속해서 업계를 선도할 수 있을까요?
Mr. Shi, it's definitely right to have a long-term vision.
시 씨, 장기적인 비전을 갖는 것은 확실히 옳습니다.
But there is no better choice than Zhanlan right now.
하지만 지금은 Zhanlan보다 더 나은 선택이 없습니다.
Are you a bit too pessimistic?
좀 너무 비관적인가요?
What does the Evaluation Department think?
평가부는 어떻게 생각하나요?
It is indeed risky for Yunchuang to make such a large investment.
Yunchuang이 그렇게 큰 투자를 하는 것은 실제로 위험합니다.
But we have done detailed calculations.
그러나 우리는 상세한 계산을 수행했습니다.
Based on Zhanlan's current profitability,
Zhanlan의 현재 수익성을 기준으로,
we believe it is a worthwhile investment opportunity.
우리는 이것이 가치 있는 투자 기회라고 믿습니다.
The prospects for solid-state batteries are indeed very promising.
전고체 배터리의 전망은 실제로 매우 밝습니다.
But the research and development cycle is long
하지만 연구개발 주기가 길다.
and the cost is huge,
그리고 비용도 엄청나고,
so we need to be careful.
그래서 우리는 조심해야 합니다.
If we want to take down Zhanlan,
잔란을 쓰러뜨리고 싶다면,
we still need to do more work.
아직 더 많은 일을 해야 해요.
But I think we can still try our best.
하지만 우리는 여전히 최선을 다할 수 있다고 생각합니다.
Everybody, Zhanlan is at the forefront of solid-state battery innovation.
여러분, Zhanlan은 전고체 배터리 혁신의 선두에 있습니다.
With our help,
우리의 도움으로,
it is possible to quickly pull away from other companies
다른 회사에서 빠르게 철수할 수 있음
and become the industry leader.
그리고 업계의 선두주자가 됩니다.
So I'm very optimistic about it.
그래서 나는 그것에 대해 매우 낙관적입니다.
But since Mr. Shi has concerns,
하지만 시씨는 걱정이 많기 때문에
we can shorten the investment cycle.
투자주기를 단축할 수 있습니다.
We can cash out quickly.
빠르게 현금화할 수 있습니다.
Since everyone is optimistic about this line of business,
모두가 이 사업 분야에 대해 낙관적이기 때문에,
let's keep pushing forward the research and evaluation work
연구와 평가 작업을 계속 추진하자
to determine the direction for the next step.
다음 단계의 방향을 결정하기 위해.
Let's end it here for today. Dismissed.
오늘은 여기서 마치겠습니다. 해고되었습니다.
Uncle Tian and Uncle Zhang are acting a bit strange today.
Tian 삼촌과 Zhang 삼촌이 오늘 좀 이상하게 행동하고 있어요.
It's not hard to understand.
이해하기 어렵지 않습니다.
Short-term large investments may bring high returns.
단기적으로 대규모 투자를 하면 높은 수익을 얻을 수 있습니다.
No investment company would give up this opportunity.
어떤 투자회사도 이 기회를 포기하지 않을 것입니다.
That's why we have so many competitors.
그렇기 때문에 우리에게는 경쟁자가 너무 많습니다.
That's their true face.
그것이 그들의 진짜 얼굴입니다.
Zhanlan is the leader in the semi-solid battery field.
Zhanlan은 반고체 배터리 분야의 선두주자입니다.
I've seen the report. They do have a lot of orders.
보고서를 본 적이 있습니다. 정말 주문이 많아요.
But their factories are all producing at an overload.
그러나 그들의 공장은 모두 과부하 상태로 생산하고 있습니다.
So, I guess the investment they got this round
그래서 이번 라운드에 투자를 받은 것 같아요.
will be spent on expanding production
생산 확대에 투자할 예정
rather than on technology research and development.
기술 연구와 개발보다는
This possibility is very high.
이 가능성은 매우 높습니다.
After all, maintaining and expanding market shares
결국 시장점유율 유지 및 확대
is the primary goal for many companies.
많은 기업의 주요 목표입니다.
What's the next step?
다음 단계는 무엇입니까?
The report is all about the past.
보고서는 모두 과거에 관한 것입니다.
I need to see the current situation with my own eyes.
현재 상황을 내 눈으로 봐야 한다.
So, I'll go and investigate in person.
그럼 제가 직접 가서 조사해보겠습니다.
Shi Yan.
시얀.
I have an idea.
나는 아이디어가.
We can start preparing.
우리는 준비를 시작할 수 있습니다.
No. What are you two talking about?
아뇨. 둘이 무슨 얘기하는 거예요?
Shi Yan.
시얀.
(Yi, have you eaten?)
(야, 밥 먹었어?)
(How have you been lately?)
(최근에 어떻게 지냈니?)
(Are you busy with work?)
(일하느라 바쁘신가요?)
It's okay.
괜찮아요.
(Do you have time this weekend?)
(이번 주말에 시간 있어요?)
Mom, why do I feel like something's off with you?
엄마, 왜 당신에게 뭔가 문제가 있는 것 같은 느낌이 들죠?
Nothing's off with me. No manners!
나에겐 아무 일도 일어나지 않습니다. 매너 없음!
I'm just concerned about you.
난 단지 당신이 걱정됩니다.
(You're concerned about the future, the things that haven't happened yet.)
(당신은 미래, 아직 일어나지 않은 일에 대해 걱정하고 있습니다.)
As the saying goes,
속담처럼,
don't be too attached to the past.
과거에 너무 집착하지 마세요.
(The future is what we should really cherish.)
(미래는 우리가 정말 소중히 여겨야 할 것입니다.)
Do.
하다.
Do you still remember what I told you last time
지난번에 제가 한 말 아직도 기억하시나요?
about the son of our dean,
우리 학장의 아들에 대해
(the one who studied abroad)
(해외에서 공부한 사람)
(and is now back in Jiangcheng?)
(지금은 Jiangcheng으로 돌아왔나요?)
Why don't you go and meet him this weekend,
이번 주말에 그 사람을 만나러 가는 게 어때요?
get to know him, and then hang out together?
그 사람을 알아가고 같이 어울리나요?
Are you trying to arrange a date for me?
나한테 데이트 약속을 주선하려고 하는 거야?
(Not at all.)
(별말씀을요.)
It's just making friends.
바로 친구를 사귀는 것입니다.
Don't young people nowadays prefer
요즘 젊은 사람들은 선호하지 않나요?
socializing online and then going out?
온라인에서 사교를 하고 나서 외출을 하시나요?
(Listen.)
(듣다.)
(This boy is quite handsome.)
(이 소년은 꽤 잘생겼다.)
I'm not doing this because of his education or family background.
나는 그의 교육이나 가족 배경 때문에 이 일을 하는 것이 아닙니다.
So, you're doing this because of his looks.
그러니까 당신은 그 사람의 외모 때문에 이런 일을 하고 있는 거죠.
(If you like him, )
(당신이 그 사람을 좋아한다면, )
(just go out with him.)
(그냥 그 사람이랑 데이트해.)
Why do you talk to your mom like this?
엄마한테 왜 이렇게 얘기해요?
No manners.
매너가 없습니다.
Do.
하다.
You're still young.
당신은 아직 젊습니다.
You can't stay single for too long.
너무 오랫동안 독신으로 지낼 수는 없습니다.
(Staying single for too long will become a habit.)
(너무 오랫동안 독신으로 지내는 것은 습관이 될 것입니다.)
(Your love life will go downhill.)
(당신의 사랑 생활은 내리막 길을 갈 것입니다.)
I'm giving you advice.
나는 당신에게 조언을 해주고 있습니다.
I really don't need it.
정말 필요하지 않습니다.
(So, say it. What kind of guys do you like?)
(그럼 말해 보세요. 어떤 남자를 좋아하시나요?)
He has to be older than me,
그 사람은 나보다 나이가 많아야 하는데,
at least 27.
적어도 27.
(Not too tall, but not too short either, )
(너무 키가 크지도, 그렇다고 너무 짧지도 않음)
around 183 cm.
183cm 정도.
It's best if he works in finance, so we'll have things to talk about.
그 사람은 금융 쪽에서 일하는 게 가장 좋으니까 얘기 좀 해봐야 할 것 같아요.
Coincidentally, he fits your requirements perfectly.
우연히도 그는 귀하의 요구 사항에 완벽하게 들어맞았습니다.
No way!
안 돼요!
Don't tell me that his name is made up of two characters too.
그의 이름도 두 글자로 구성되어 있다고 말하지 마십시오.
You guessed it right!
당신의 추측이 맞았습니다!
(I'm sending his WeChat to you now.)
(지금 그의 WeChat을 당신에게 보내고 있습니다.)
Add him.
그를 추가해라.
There are pictures on his WeChat.
그의 WeChat에 사진이 있습니다.
Take a look and you'll know
한번 살펴보면 알게 될 것이다
if what I said about him is accurate.
내가 그에 대해 말한 것이 정확하다면.
(If you don't think you guys are suitable...)
(당신이 적합하지 않다고 생각한다면 ...)
Can you just stop introducing guys to me again?
이제 나한테 남자 소개 좀 그만해줄래?
Oh, it's all right if it's not suitable.
아, 적합하지 않아도 괜찮아요.
I will keep introducing
계속 소개할게요
(until you're satisfied.)
(만족하실 때까지)
(How about it? Is it good?)
(어때요? 좋은가요?)
All right then.
그럼요.
I'm going to meet a new friend then.
그럼 난 새로운 친구를 만나러 갈 거야.
As I told you, this guy is pretty good, right?
아까 말했듯이 이 사람 꽤 괜찮지 않나요?
Remember to go to the meeting on the weekend, alright?
주말에 회의에 가는 거 잊지 마세요, 그렇죠?
Meeting.
회의.
Mom, I'm hanging up now. I have to go to a meeting.
엄마, 나 지금 전화 끊는 중이에요. 나는 회의에 가야 해요.
Shu Yi.
슈이.
Yu Ling.
유 링.
You two have attended Yunchuang's press conference before.
두 분은 이전에도 윤추앙의 기자회견에 참석한 적이 있습니다.
The year-end cover for next month will be entrusted to you two.
다음 달 연말 표지는 두 분에게 맡깁니다.
I hope you two can work together
너희 둘이 함께 일할 수 있기를 바라
to give Financial Introduce a good ending this year.
올해 파이낸셜 인트로듀스도 좋은 마무리를 하기 위해.
That's settled then.
그러면 해결되었습니다.
Shu Yi, you're in charge of finalizing the article.
슈이님, 기사 마무리를 담당하고 계시네요.
Do you two have any other questions?
두 분 또 다른 질문 있으신가요?
No.
아니요.
Everyone has been doing great lately.
최근 다들 잘 지내고 있어요.
Keep up the good work.
계속해서 좋은 일을 하세요.
There are only two more issues left this year.
올해는 딱 두 문제만 남았습니다.
Don't slack off.
느슨해지지 마십시오.
Put in more effort. Then, have a great new year ahead.
더 많은 노력을 기울이십시오. 그럼 새해 복 많이 받으세요.
All right. Dismissed.
괜찮은. 해고되었습니다.
Shu Yi.
슈이.
Come to my office.
내 사무실로 오세요.
You've been doing well lately.
최근에 잘 지내셨어요.
The editor-in-chief and I have high hopes for you.
편집장과 나는 당신에게 큰 기대를 걸고 있습니다.
The deputy editor position has been empty for a while.
부편집장 자리가 한동안 비어 있었습니다.
Work hard
열심히 일하다
and try to surpass me.
그리고 나를 뛰어넘으려고 노력해 보세요.
Ms. Yi, you know that this is not my end goal.
이 선생님, 이것이 제 최종 목표가 아니라는 걸 아시잖아요.
Shu Yi.
슈이.
No matter what form it takes,
어떤 형태를 취하더라도,
the most important thing is the article itself.
가장 중요한 것은 기사 자체입니다.
A good article is the same no matter where it's placed.
좋은 글은 어디에 놓아도 똑같습니다.
But articles and interviews have time limits.
하지만 기사와 인터뷰에는 시간 제한이 있습니다.
Interaction with the readers is also important.
독자와의 상호작용도 중요하다.
The editor-in-chief has his own considerations.
편집장은 자신의 고려 사항을 가지고 있습니다.
Regarding the current state of print media,
현재의 인쇄매체 현황에 대해
we in Financial Introduce have already made our calculations.
Financial Introduce에서는 이미 계산을 했습니다.
If we add more people and budget,
인력과 예산을 더 추가하면
it would be difficult for him.
그에게는 어려울 것입니다.
This is exactly why I want to promote a digital magazine.
이것이 바로 제가 디지털 매거진을 홍보하고 싶은 이유입니다.
I want to meet the readers' needs and reading habits.
독자들의 요구와 독서 습관을 충족시키고 싶습니다.
It might be a new way out.
새로운 탈출구가 될 수도 있습니다.
I understand your point.
나는 당신의 요점을 이해합니다.
But the reality is that Financial Introduce is a monthly magazine.
하지만 현실은 파이낸셜인트로듀스가 월간지라는 점이다.
Our current structure is just right.
우리의 현재 구조는 딱 맞습니다.
If we put all our energy into the digital magazine,
우리가 디지털 매거진에 온 힘을 쏟는다면,
we would need a lot of articles,
기사가 많이 필요할 텐데,
and we would need more manpower and financial resources
더 많은 인력과 재정 자원이 필요할 것입니다.
to make it happen.
그것을 실현하기 위해.
I get it.
알겠습니다.
That's why I wanted to try it.
그래서 나는 그것을 시도하고 싶었습니다.
I can write articles for both paper and digital magazines.
나는 종이 잡지와 디지털 잡지 모두에 기사를 쓸 수 있습니다.
I can do both with the current team.
나는 현재 팀에서 두 가지를 모두 할 수 있다.
Finish the work for this year first.
올해의 일을 먼저 끝내세요.
Then, think carefully about the new-year cover next year.
그렇다면 내년 새해 표지에 대해 잘 생각해 보세요.
If you do it well,
잘만 하면,
I will try to talk to the editor-in-chief about the digital magazine.
디지털 매거진에 관해 편집장과 이야기를 나눠보도록 하겠습니다.
Thank you, Ms. Yi.
고마워요, 이씨.
Professor Yu.
유 교수.
I didn't expect you to be my date.
당신이 내 데이트 상대가 될 줄은 몰랐어요.
Shu Yi.
슈이.
Sit.
앉다.
So, you already knew that I was your date?
그럼 내가 데이트 상대인 걸 이미 알고 있었나요?
As soon as I saw it was you I felt relieved immediately.
당신이라는 걸 보자마자 바로 안도감을 느꼈어요.
You even dressed up.
심지어 옷까지 차려입으셨네요.
Since it's a date with a professor, I had to dress up
교수님과의 데이트라서 옷을 입어야 했어요
at least out of respect.
적어도 존경심에서.
Since you knew it was me,
나인 줄 알았으니까
why didn't you tell me earlier through WeChat?
왜 아까 위챗으로 나한테 말하지 않았어?
My mom is a crafty one.
우리 엄마는 교활한 사람이에요.
If I had talked to you,
내가 당신과 이야기를 나누었다면,
she would have asked to see the chat log,
그녀는 채팅 기록을 보여달라고 요청했을 것이고,
and then she would have known that we already knew each other.
그러면 그녀는 우리가 이미 서로를 알고 있다는 것을 알았을 것입니다.
What would you like to drink? I'll order for you.
뭐 마시고 싶어요? 내가 주문할게요.
Anything is fine.
무엇이든 괜찮습니다.
Waitress.
웨이트리스.
(Does it look good?)
(좋아 보이는데요?)
(Give me a two-word answer.)
(두 단어로 대답해주세요.)
(Looks okay.)
(괜찮아 보이는데.)
(When will you come and take your things back?)
(언제 오셔서 물건을 다시 가져가실 건가요?)
Shu Yi. It's already this late.
슈이. 벌써 이렇게 늦었어.
Let's have lunch together later.
나중에 같이 점심 먹자.
It's okay. I'm not hungry yet.
괜찮아요. 아직 배가 고프지 않아요.
I still have something to do later.
나중에 할 일이 아직 남아 있어요.
I'll make an appointment with you next time.
다음에 꼭 약속을 잡을게요.
Okay.
좋아요.
(What did I forget to bring back with me?)
(내가 무엇을 가져오는 것을 잊었나요?)
(Mr. Shi.)
(시 씨.)
(Are you talking about my heart?)
(내 마음을 말하는 거야?)
(The clothes you bought the day we went to the banquet.)
(연회에 갔던 날 사준 옷.)
I forgot all about it.
나는 그것에 대해 모두 잊어 버렸습니다.
Oh, snap. I can't return it if I wait any longer.
아, 스냅. 더 기다리면 돌려드릴 수 없어요.
(I've been too busy lately.)
(요즘 너무 바빴어요.)
(I forgot.)
(깜빡했어요.)
(Can you help me deliver it, please?)
(배달을 도와주실 수 있나요?)
(I need it urgently.)
(급하게 필요해요.)
(Pretty please.)
(예뻐요.)
(I'm also very busy lately.)
(저도 최근에 너무 바빠요.)
(I have no time to be a courier.)
(택배를 할 시간이 없습니다.)
(What are you busy with?)
(무슨 일로 바쁘세요?)
(Making desserts?)
(디저트를 만드나요?)
Is this joke never going to go away?
이 농담은 결코 사라지지 않을 것입니까?
(I'll go get it now.)
(지금 찾으러 갈게요.)
(Wait for me.)
(날 기다려.)
Excuse me, sir. I want to go to another place.
실례합니다. 나는 다른 곳으로 가고 싶다.
Okay.
좋아요.
Yue.
유에.
Give your uncle a call.
삼촌에게 전화해 보세요.
Okay.
좋아요.
- Hello? - (Uncle.)
- 안녕하세요? - (삼촌.)
(Dinner is ready. When are you coming back?)
(저녁 준비됐어요. 언제 오세요?)
You guys go ahead and eat. I won't be coming back.
여러분, 가서 식사하세요. 나는 돌아오지 않을 것이다.
Come back after you're done with your work. We can wait for you.
일을 마친 후에 다시 오세요. 우리는 당신을 기다릴 수 있습니다.
It doesn't matter how late.
얼마나 늦었는지는 중요하지 않습니다.
You and Grandpa eat first.
당신과 할아버지가 먼저 식사를 하세요.
I have something to do.
나는 할일이있어.
(But you need to eat too.)
(근데 너도 먹어야 해.)
I'm already cooking.
나는 이미 요리 중입니다.
Grandpa. Uncle said he's already cooking.
할아버지. 삼촌은 이미 요리를 하고 있다고 하더군요.
- He won't be coming back for dinner. - Give me the phone.
- 그 사람은 저녁 먹으러 돌아오지 않을 거예요. - 전화 주세요.
Shi Yan.
시얀.
You haven't been home for dinner for quite a few days.
당신은 꽤 오랫동안 저녁을 먹으러 집에 들어오지 않았습니다.
Dad, I'll make time to come back in two days.
아빠, 이틀 뒤에 시간을 내서 다시 올게요.
(I heard)
(들었어요)
you've been seeing a female actress recently.
최근에 여자 배우를 만났어요.
Who told you that?
누가 그런 말을 했나요?
You can't find the source for most rumors.
대부분의 소문의 출처를 찾을 수 없습니다.
Just answer me. Yes or no?
그냥 대답해 주세요. 예 혹은 아니오?
No. She just wants to show off a bit.
아뇨. 그냥 좀 자랑하고 싶을 뿐이에요.
(Dad, I'm hanging up now.)
(아빠, 나 지금 전화 끊는 중이에요.)
(Something happened.)
(무슨 일이 일어났습니다.)
Grandpa. Uncle is really in love.
할아버지. 삼촌은 정말 사랑에 빠졌습니다.
Done with work? Where did you come from?
일이 끝났나요? 당신은 어디서 왔나요?
Come in.
올.
So many dishes!
요리가 너무 많아요!
(You're so silly.)
(당신은 정말 바보입니다.)
Mr. Shi.
시 씨.
I've been busy all day. I haven't even eaten yet.
나는 하루 종일 바빴다. 아직 식사도 안 했어요.
Look at this big table of dishes.
이 커다란 접시들 좀 보세요.
You can't finish them all by yourself.
혼자서는 다 끝낼 수 없습니다.
It's too wasteful.
너무 낭비입니다.
If you don't want to waste it,
낭비하고 싶지 않다면,
sit down and eat it all.
앉아서 다 먹어요.
Thank you for the hospitality. I will definitely respect the food,
환대에 감사드립니다. 나는 음식을 확실히 존중할 것입니다.
and eat it all without leaving anything.
그리고 남기지 않고 다 먹습니다.
That's so delicious!
정말 맛있어요!
Which takeout is this? How come it tastes so good?
이건 어떤 테이크아웃인가요? 어쩜 이렇게 맛이 좋은 걸까요?
It's a place you can't order from.
주문할 수 없는 곳이에요.
Why do you look down on me?
왜 나를 무시합니까?
It's too delicious.
너무 맛있어요.
If I could have this kind of food every time I wake up,
아침에 일어날 때마다 이런 음식을 먹을 수 있다면,
that would be so blessed.
정말 축복받은 일이겠죠.
It's not hard either.
어렵지도 않습니다.
You're right, Mr. Shi.
당신 말이 맞아요, 시 씨.
As long as I work hard,
내가 열심히 일하는 한,
I can also afford such delicious food.
나도 이렇게 맛있는 음식을 먹을 수 있다.
So,
그래서,
what do you think about
당신은 무엇을 생각합니까
the Mingyu Yunchuang's special report
민규운창 특별보고
that I mentioned to you before?
내가 전에 말했던 거요?
Can we continue to push it forward?
계속해서 추진할 수 있을까요?
I don't talk about work during my private time.
나는 사적인 시간에는 일에 대해 이야기하지 않는다.
And, she said it's not hard.
그리고 그녀는 어렵지 않다고 말했습니다.
Don't talk while eating. This may cause indigestion.
식사하는 동안 말하지 마세요. 이로 인해 소화불량이 발생할 수 있습니다.
(Shu Yi. Do you have time now?)
(슈이. 지금 시간 있어요?)
(Let's talk over the phone.)
(전화로 얘기하자.)
Looking at your phone while eating is bad for your stomach.
식사하면서 휴대폰을 보는 것은 위장에 좋지 않습니다.
(Ms. Yi. It's not convenient now. I'll call back later.)
(이씨. 지금은 불편해요. 나중에 다시 전화할게요.)
Mr. Shi, I'm done eating.
시 씨, 밥 다 먹었어요.
Mr. Shi, where's my stuff?
미스터 시, 내 물건은 어디에 있나요?
Here you go.
여기요.
Thank you, Mr. Shi.
고마워요, 시 씨.
- Zheng Shu Yi. - No need to see me off.
-정수이. - 배웅할 필요 없어요.
Goodbye, Mr. Shi.
안녕히 계세요, 시 씨.
You really love taking things and hanging around for free meals.
당신은 물건을 가지고 돌아다니는 것을 정말 좋아하고 무료 식사를 즐기기도 합니다.
(Shu Yi, in two days, there will be)
(슈이, 이틀 후면 나올 거야)
(an international industry forum in Wucheng.)
(Wucheng에서 열린 국제 산업 포럼)
(You should attend the event.)
(이벤트에 참여하셔야 합니다.)
Okay, I'll set off tomorrow.
알았어, 내일 출발할게.
(Thanks for your hard work.)
(노력해 주셔서 감사합니다.)
Shan Shan.
샨샨.
I've visited Bogang Yunwan three times.
나는 보강윤완을 세 번이나 방문했다.
Shan Shan, this way.
샨샨, 이쪽이에요.
Sorry for being late.
늦어서 죄송합니다.
Come here. Have a drink.
이리 오세요. 한잔하세요.
- You should be punished with a drink. - Okay.
- 술로 벌을 받아야 한다. - 좋아요.
- Fill it up. - Come on.
- 채워주세요. - 어서 해봐요.
Fill it up.
그것을 채우십시오.
Excuse me for a moment.
잠시 실례합니다.
- Great! - You're a good drinker.
- 엄청난! - 당신은 술을 잘 마십니다.
Not bad.
나쁘지 않다.
- Hello. - Long time no see.
- 안녕하세요. - 오랜만이에요.
- Hello. - Hi.
- 안녕하세요. - 안녕.
Shan Shan. You know him, right?
샨샨. 그 사람 알지?
The prince from the Guan family.
관 가문의 왕자.
The CEO of Guan Capital.
관캐피탈의 CEO.
I met him once at the press conference.
기자간담회에서 그를 한 번 만났다.
Shan Shan is a beautiful journalist from Interactive Entertainment Net.
Shan Shan은 Interactive Entertainment Net의 아름다운 저널리스트입니다.
Miss Bi
미스비
looks even better in person than on camera.
카메라로 보는 것보다 직접 보는 것이 훨씬 더 좋아 보입니다.
Shan Shan. You have to be careful.
샨샨. 조심해야합니다.
Mr. Guan is really a sweet-talker.
관씨는 정말 말을 잘하는 사람이에요.
He's a killer of beauties.
그는 미인을 죽이는 사람입니다.
But he's no match for me.
하지만 그 사람은 나와 어울리지 않아요.
I don't like sweet talk.
나는 달콤한 말을 좋아하지 않는다.
I like spicy food.
나는 매운 음식을 좋아한다.
Come on. Let me treat everyone to a drink.
어서 해봐요. 모두에게 한잔씩 대접하겠습니다.
- Come on. - Cheers.
- 어서 해봐요. - 건배.
Qin Shi Yue really made a great contribution
Qin Shi Yue는 정말 큰 공헌을 했습니다.
to Jiangcheng's with her own might.
자신의 힘으로 Jiangcheng에게.
Hi there, delivery.
안녕하세요, 배달입니다.
Miss. Are you running an online store?
Miss. 온라인 매장을 운영하시나요?
No. I'm returning them.
아뇨. 돌려드릴게요.
All of them?
그들 모두?
What kind of store is this? The quality is so bad.
이 가게는 어떤 가게인가요? 품질이 너무 나쁩니다.
I bought too much. Sorry to trouble you.
너무 많이 샀어요. 불편을 끼쳐드려 죄송합니다.
Not at all.
별말씀을요.
How can I get to know him?
어떻게 하면 그 사람을 알 수 있나요?
I should at least try to get his WeChat.
적어도 그의 WeChat을 얻으려고 노력해야합니다.
Yue.
유에.
Don't be lazy.
게으르지 마십시오.
I'm watching you on behalf of Shu Yi.
슈이를 대신해서 지켜보고 있어요.
I've wronged you.
나는 당신에게 잘못했습니다.
You're making quite a progress.
당신은 꽤 발전하고 있습니다.
Yu You is popular.
유유는 인기가 많아요.
He's worth studying.
그 사람은 공부할 가치가 있어요.
I remember Shu Yi seems to have
Shu Yi가 그랬던 것으로 기억합니다.
gone to the University of Finance and Economics to interview him.
그를 인터뷰하기 위해 재경대학에 갔다.
Do more homework.
숙제를 더 많이 하세요.
It will be of great help in the future.
앞으로도 큰 도움이 될 것입니다.
Gone to the University of Finance and Economics to interview him?
그를 인터뷰하기 위해 재경대학에 갔습니까?
For us finance students,
우리 금융학생들에게는
we all probably have a dream to become an investor.
우리 모두는 투자자가 되고 싶은 꿈을 가지고 있을 것입니다.
So, what's the most important thing for an investor?
그렇다면 투자자에게 가장 중요한 것은 무엇일까요?
A very important key is to learn DD.
매우 중요한 열쇠는 DD를 배우는 것입니다.
What is DD?
DD란 무엇인가요?
DD stands for due diligence.
DD는 실사(Due Diligence)를 의미합니다.
It's an investigation conducted by the investor
투자자가 실시한 조사입니다.
and intermediary institutions,
중개기관,
with the cooperation of the business,
업체의 협조를 받아,
on aspects such as the business's historical data and documents,
비즈니스의 과거 데이터 및 문서와 같은 측면에 대해
management background,
경영배경,
market risks, management risks, technical risks, and capital risks.
시장리스크, 경영리스크, 기술리스크, 자본리스크 등으로 구성됩니다.
It's a comprehensive and in-depth review,
종합적이고 심층적인 리뷰입니다.
and the cycle is usually three to six months.
그리고 그 주기는 보통 3~6개월이다.
I didn't expect him not to wear a suit and still look so handsome.
그가 양복을 입지 않고 여전히 이렇게 잘생길 줄은 몰랐다.
He's even more handsome than at the press conference.
기자간담회 ​​때보다 더 잘생겼네요.
Oh, my God.
맙소사.
Please give me such a university lecturer.
그런 대학 강사를 주세요.
For the recitation of the definitions,
정의를 암송하려면,
I believe everyone must feel that it's very boring.
모두가 매우 지루하다고 느낄 것이라고 생각합니다.
But the knowledge points just mentioned are very important,
하지만 방금 언급한 지식 포인트는 매우 중요합니다.
especially the four risks.
특히 네 가지 위험.
Everyone must remember those.
모두가 그것을 기억해야합니다.
The next in-class test will definitely cover them.
다음 강의실 테스트에서는 확실히 이를 다룰 것입니다.
Hurry up and take note.
서둘러서 메모해 두세요.
For some things, just looking at the surface isn't enough.
어떤 것에는 표면만 보는 것만으로는 충분하지 않습니다.
We need to investigate and understand more deeply and carefully.
우리는 좀 더 깊고 세심하게 조사하고 이해해야 합니다.
Where are we now?
지금 우리는 어디에 있나요?
We just started with the definition,
방금 정의부터 시작했는데,
and it might seem a bit hard to understand.
이해하기가 조금 어려울 수도 있습니다.
Let's simplify it a bit.
조금 단순화해 보겠습니다.
Let's relate it to our daily lives.
이를 우리의 일상생활과 연관시켜 보겠습니다.
If you want to get to know someone you are not familiar with
모르는 사람과 친해지고 싶다면
or don't yet know,
아니면 아직 모르거나,
we would certainly want to know as much as possible about him.
우리는 그에 대해 가능한 한 많은 것을 알고 싶을 것입니다.
At this time, everyone will definitely
이때쯤 되면 다들 분명
do some background checks
배경 조사를 좀 해라
from different dimensions and levels
다양한 차원과 수준에서
to understand the relevant information about this person in all aspects,
이 사람에 대한 관련 정보를 모든 측면에서 이해하고,
so as to make up for the asymmetric
비대칭을 보완하기 위해
and imperfect information between the two parties.
그리고 두 당사자 간의 불완전한 정보.
That's it.
그게 다야.
If there's anything you don't understand, ask me.
이해가 안 되는 부분이 있으면 저에게 물어보세요.
- Professor Yu, we're leaving. - Thank you, professor.
- 유 교수님, 우리는 떠나겠습니다. - 감사합니다, 교수님.
- Bye. - Bye.
- 안녕. - 안녕.
Professor Yu.
유 교수.
Can I add you on WeChat?
WeChat에 당신을 추가해도 될까요?
I want to ask you about some parts I don't understand.
제가 이해하지 못하는 부분에 대해 질문드리고 싶습니다.
You can ask me whatever you don't understand now.
이제 이해가 안 되는 부분은 무엇이든 물어보셔도 됩니다.
Where don't you understand?
어디가 이해가 안 되나요?
Professor Yu. Don't you remember me?
유 교수. 나를 기억하지 못하시나요?
Last time, you helped me get coffee at the financial center
저번에 금융센터에서 커피 마시는 걸 도와줬는데
during Yunchuang's press conference.
윤추앙 기자회견 중.
I still remember. Is there something you need me for?
나는 아직도 기억한다. 내가 꼭 필요한 일이라도 있어?
I wanted to meet you!
나는 당신을 만나고 싶었습니다!
Last time, I didn't have the chance to add you on WeChat.
지난번에는 WeChat에 당신을 추가할 기회가 없었습니다.
You ran around half of Jiangcheng
당신은 강성(Jangcheng)의 절반을 돌았습니다.
just to add me on WeChat?
그냥 나를 WeChat에 추가하려고요?
It's not just that.
그것만이 아니다.
I'm an intern journalist for Financial Introduce.
저는 Financial Introduce의 인턴 기자입니다.
I just came here to learn.
나는 단지 배우려고 여기에 왔습니다.
You're a journalist for Financial Introduce too?
당신도 Financial Introduce의 기자이신가요?
Yes. I'm an intern.
예. 저는 인턴이에요.
Shu Yi is my supervisor.
Shu Yi는 내 상사입니다.
So, you're under Shu Yi?
그럼 당신은 Shu Yi 밑에 있는 겁니까?
Can I come to your class next time?
다음번에 네 수업에 와도 될까?
Yes.
예.
But, one thing. Don't fall asleep next time.
하지만 한 가지. 다음에는 잠들지 마세요.
I'm teaching finance.
저는 금융을 가르치고 있어요.
You can search for the learning materials online.
온라인으로 학습자료를 검색하실 수 있습니다.
If you can't find them,
찾을 수 없다면,
remember to tell me before the next class,
다음 수업 전에 나한테 꼭 말해 줘.
and I'll help you prepare.
그리고 내가 준비하는 것을 도와줄게.
What?
무엇?
You just ate and left with the bag?
밥만 먹고 가방을 가지고 나갔나요?
Right.
오른쪽.
(You're really something, Zheng Shu Yi.)
(당신은 정말 대단해요, Zheng Shu Yi.)
But the editor was looking for me. What could I do?
그런데 편집자가 나를 찾고 있었어요. 내가 무엇을 할 수 있나요?
No wonder Shi Yan didn't take you seriously.
Shi Yan이 당신을 진지하게 받아들이지 않은 것도 당연합니다.
So, what do you suggest I do now?
그럼 이제 제가 무엇을 하라고 제안하시나요?
Where are you now?
지금 어디 있나요?
(I'm on a business trip in Wucheng.)
(저는 우청으로 출장중입니다.)
Okay. Take a picture and post it on your WeChat Moments.
좋아요. 사진을 찍어 WeChat Moments에 게시하세요.
(What should I say?)
(무슨 말을 해야 할까요?)
Nothing.
아무것도 아님.
Nothing?
아무것도 아님?
(Just follow my lead.)
(그냥 내 지시를 따르세요.)
If you've encountered anything interesting,
흥미로운 것을 접하셨다면,
remember to post it on your WeChat Moments.
WeChat Moments에 게시하는 것을 잊지 마세요.
Got it.
알았어요.